Hello and welcome
to Real Easy English,
the podcast where we have
real conversations in easy English
to help you learn.
I'm Beth.
And I'm Neil.
There is a video version
of this podcast on our website,
where you can also find a worksheet
and transcript to help you learn.
It's at bbclearningenglish.com.
Hi, Neil.
How are you?
I'm hungry.
Me too. I'm starving.
Well, that's good, because
we're talking about lunch today.
We're recording this just
before lunch, so it's no wonder that
we're both very hungry.
You might be able to hear our
tummies rumble because we're hungry.
OK. So, shall we begin?
Yes. Let's do it.
What have you got for lunch today?
Today for my lunch, I have chicken
with potatoes and vegetables
in a harissa paste.
Oh, that sounds really nice.
Yeah, it's leftovers actually,
which I have heated up
and brought in, in a little flask.
What are leftovers?
Good question. Leftovers.
That's food from a meal that you've
already had that you didn't finish
and you can heat it up
and eat it again.
Yes. I also have leftovers
for my lunch today.
So, yesterday I made a pasta for lunch
with vegetables in it
and I have that.
So, Beth, what do you usually have
for lunch?
Is it usually leftovers
or something else?
It's usually leftovers when I come
into work because it's easier,
and then I don't need to buy lunch.
But if I go out and buy food,
then I would usually go for something
like sushi or ramen.
What about you?
What do you usually have for lunch?
Yeah. Sometimes I have leftovers
that I bring in.
Sometimes I buy a sandwich,
for example.
What's your favourite kind
of sandwich?
If I have a sandwich...
if I buy a sandwich for lunch, I like
to get things like smoked salmon.
Nice, with pickles maybe.
Yeah.
There's a really good baguette I like
actually that has smoked salmon
and egg mayonnaise in it.
Oh, it's so nice.
Stop it.
Sorry.
I'm so hungry.
Me too. Neil, do you ever skip lunch?
No. No way!
I would be in a horrible mood
if I skipped lunch.
I don't understand
how anyone can skip any meal.
I need to eat all my meals.
Yeah. Otherwise, you get hangry.
Exactly. 'Hangry' is hungry and angry.
I'm on the...
I'm almost getting hangry now.
What's your favourite meal?
Is it lunch?
Breakfast? Dinner?
I think the evening meal is probably
my favourite because we sit at the table
and chat and it's the biggest,
nicest meal of the day
and you don't really have to do
anything after so you can relax.
Mmm. Yeah, that's good.
I really like brunch, which is
that sort of in between breakfast
and lunch – maybe 10:00.
And I might have eggs and bacon
and hash browns and avocado,
a big meal full of lots of good food.
I like a brunch.
Do you ever have a working lunch?
I do occasionally
if I'm working from home.
because I can carry on working
and eat quickly.
And then in my actual lunch break,
I might have a nice long walk
or something like that,
but when I'm in the office,
I don't want to eat at my desk.
No. Me neither.
I don't really like working lunches.
I would rather eat my lunch
without working.
Yeah, I'd prefer the same, really.
Let's recap the language we heard
during the conversation.
We had 'skip',
which means not have or do.
For example, I never skip lunch.
We heard 'working lunch', which is when
you eat your lunch while you're working.
We also had 'leftovers',
which is when you don't finish a meal
so you have more of it at
a different time, like the next day.
And we talked about which meals
and food we 'prefer'.
If you prefer something, you like it
better than something else.
Yes. And another phrase we can use
to say this is 'would rather'.
For example, I'd rather have sushi
than a sandwich for lunch.
That's it for this episode
of Real Easy English.
Test what you've learned
with a worksheet on our website,
bbclearningenglish.com.
And make sure you join us again for
another easy English conversation.
We'll be back next week.
See you soon.
Goodbye!